

# **DENNIS HERRIS**

dherris@gmail.com / 760-455-6404 Vista, CA 92084

#### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated Senior Quality Assurance Engineer bringing 24+ years of experience and diligence to handle needs of large and complex products. Solid history in manual testing with some automated testing background. Seek to apply expertise to growth-oriented, dynamic position.

#### **SKILLS**

- Agile software development
- Project management
- Release optimization
- Scrum methodology
- Test planning
- Cross-platform testing
- Defect resolution
- Team management
- Operational improvement
- Planning and coordination
- Supervision
- Process improvement
- Project organization
- Problem resolution
- Amazon Web Services
- Testing and deployment

- JIRA
- MySQL
- SQL
- API Testing
- Jenkins
- Offshore Team Management
- Automation familiarity
- Test script development
- Software system testing
- Test case development
- Java
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- NodeJS
- GitHub

### **EXPERIENCE**

Senior Quality Assurance Engineer / Tealium Inc. - San Diego, CA

02/2017 - 08/2020

- Performed Manual Regression, End to End, Boundary, and Ad Hoc tests according to strict production schedules.
- Developed efficient and thorough test cases and scripts using CucumberStudio/Hiptest to facilitate consistent approach to product development in agile environment.
- Conducted product demonstrations and showcased functionality to customers, team leaders and colleagues.
- Executed existing automated testing scripts with Selenium.
- Worked alongside developers and other project stakeholders to understand function, features and testing needs of each program.
- Teamed with in-house and offshore teams to test web, mobile and client-server software applications for Sales and Marketing Data Collection.

- Worked with software programs developed in languages such as Javascript UI using React/Node.js and full stack backend Java components to update to new platforms, conduct testing and provide integration functionality with new platforms.
- Performed API testing using Postman.

### Senior Quality Assurance Engineer / Adicio Inc. - Carlsbad, CA

09/2006 - 12/2016

- Web/Internet testing of online job posting boards, real estate ads, and motors applications created with HTML, ASP, PHP, XML, and JAVA, SOLR, and MySQL Database
- In charge of hiring, building, and implementing processes for a Quality Assurance team that did not exist previously at this company.
- HTTPS 40-bit and 128-bit encryption testing
- Managed and mentored a testing team of three.
- Project Lead on a variety of software projects.
- Developed Test Plans, Test Cases, Executed Test Scripts Manually, Defined Test Metrics, Logged Defects, Agile Software Development, and attended production meetings
- Performed testing using IE, Chrome, and Firefox browsers
- Defects tracked using Jira, Rally, NetOffice, and Sales Force
- Communicated with Developers, Project Managers, System Administrators, Product Managers, Implementation Managers, and VP's

# Senior Quality Assurance Analyst/Offshore Supervisor / Irvine Technology Corporation - Poway, CA 10/2000 - 08/2006

- Contract with First American Interactive Division
- Web/Internet testing of online financial applications created with HTML, ASP, VB, XML, and .Net, using SQL 2000 and Oracle Databases
- HTTPS 40-bit and 128-bit encryption testing
- Managed and mentored a testing team of eight in India.
- Managed an offshore team that had zero severity one defects reported by customers during our testing for two
  plus years.
- RUP (Rational Unified Process) standard concepts, practices, and procedures
- Executed and updated Rational Robot and QTP scripts.
- Project Lead on a variety of software projects
- Developed Test Plans, Test Cases, Executed Test Scripts Manually, Defined Test Metrics, Logged Defects, and attended production meetings
- Performed testing using IE 4.0-6.0 and Netscape 4.6-6.0 browsers
- Defects tracked using Rational ClearQuest
- Coordinated with Change Management Team to finalize deployment builds
- Communicated with QA Manager, Developers, Project Managers, Netops, Change Management, Business Analysts and VP's
- MS Windows NT 4.0 (Server), 98, and 2000 (Server)

# **Lead Quality Assurance Analyst/Automation Test Lead** / TriTech Software Systems - San Diego, CA 11/1996 - 10/2000

- Client Server and Website testing of Computer Aided Dispatching software created for use by Fire, Ambulance, and Police Departments worldwide
- Involved in automation of the client server application using Rational Robot 7.5
- Black box testing on client server application developed in Visual Basic 6 with a SQL 7 database
- Black box testing on Web Based application using IE 4.01 and greater
- Performed Crystal Reports testing for all reporting databases
- Entered defects using DevTrack
- Participated in writing over 6,400 manual test scripts
- Managed a team of three that created UI automated test scripts for the 6400 manual test scripts
- Communicated with QA Manager, Developers, Project Managers, Netops, Business Administrators and CEO's.
- MS Windows NT 4.0 and NT Server 4.0

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Coleman University - San Diego, CA

Computer Information of Science Certification: Computer Information Science

09/1996

University of California - San Diego - La Jolla, CA

Expected in 03/2021

Full Stack Web Development Certification: Full Stack Web Development

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- OS/Services: MS-DOS, Windows 3.1, 95, NT 4.0 and NT Server 4.0, 98, 2000, XP, OS X, OS/400, and AWS Services
- Automated Testing Tools: Selenium, Rational Robot, and Mercury QuickTest Pro
- Defect Tracking Systems: Jira, Rally, ClearQuest, DevTrack, Bugzilla, Trello, and in house systems
- Remote Software: Pulse Secure, PCAnywhere, Open VPN Connect, and VPN
- Platforms / Languages: Turbo C/C++, Visual Basic, COBOL, RPG, UNIX, PL/1, and Visual FoxPro
- Database Platforms: SOLR, Access, Oracle, Microsoft SQL, Sybase SQL Anywhere, Oracle, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, PrestoDB, and MySQL